Teachers Union of the City of New York Records 5015
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Academic Freedom, Hyman Koppelman, 1940-1953 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  Record of service, cases, report, telegram, correspondence, hearings, statement
- Academic Freedom, Maurice Kunzman, 1953-1954 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  News clippings, case, interview, statements, telegram, form letters, correspondence, appeal
- Academic Freedom, Lorch, Lee (City College), 1949 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  Memo's, brief, resolution, press release, telegram, correspondence, form letter, case, statement, announcements
- Academic Freedom, Loyalty Oaths, 1950-1959 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  Pamphlets, form letters, press release, correspondence, bulletin, memo, news clippings, appeal
- Academic Freedom, McCarthyism - effects on Science and Education, 1957 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  Address, correspondence, news clippings
- Academic Freedom, Gladys Mann, 1949 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  Correspondence, report, news clippings
- Academic Freedom, Massachusetts, 1955 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  Legal paper, publication
- Academic Freedom, Meeting, 1939-1940 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  News clipping, correspondence, bulletin, leaflet
- Academic Freedom, Meiklejohn, Alexander, 1953-1959 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  Press release, telegram, correspondence, program, news clippings, statement, address,
- Academic Freedom, Agnes 1. Meyer, 1953-1956 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  News releases, speeches, addresses, correspondence, memo, news clippings, publication
- Academic Freedom, Arthur Miller, 1950-1957 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  Correspondence, news clippings, remarks
- Academic Freedom, miscellaneous, 1950-1960 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  Press releases, news clippings, bulletins, act, pamphlet, publication, correspondence, statements
- Academic Freedom, Broadus Mitchell, 1953-1955 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  Correspondence, news clippings, reprint, report
- Academic Freedom, "Nation" "banning Ad Hoc Committee, 1948-1950 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  Correspondence, telegram, press releases, news clippings, statement, card
- Academic Freedom, "Nation" banning, correspondence, 1948-1949 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  Telegrams, correspondence, who's who among signers of appeal
- Academic Freedom, "Nation" banning, mimeo material, 1948-1949 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  Press releases, statements, correspondence, brief, declaration, appeal
- Academic Freedom, "Nation" banning, printed material, 1948-1949 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  Publications, brief, leaflets
- Academic Freedom, Needleman, Morriss, 1949-1950 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  Press releases, correspondence, hearing, news clipping, leaflet
- Academic Freedom, Needleman, Morriss, 1949-1951 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  Photocopies, correspondence, Needleman Record, memo, analysis, briefs
- Academic Freedom, Newark Cases, 1953-1955 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  Minutes, correspondence, leaflets, announcement, publication, news clippings
- Academic Freedom, Newark Cases, 1955-1961 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  Publication, news clippings, weekly bulletin, brief, case, decision
- Academic Freedom, Arthur Newman, 1945-1953 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  Material found, press release, interview, statements excerpts, report, telegram, hearing, bulletins, invitation, cards, correspondence, form letters
- Academic Freedom, Objective Teaching, 1938-1954 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  Correspondence, invitation, news clippings, press release, questionnaire
- Academic Freedom, Out-of-town and foreign, 1949-1963 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  Reports, news clippings, bulletin, press release, statements, publication, correspondence
- Academic Freedom, PTA Loyalty Oath (Barnes Bill), 1954 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  Form letter, releases, news clippings, notes
- Academic Freedom, Pennsylvania Loyalty Oath, (Teachers Union of Philadelphia), 1951 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  Correspondence, testimony, opinion, press releases, publications, memo, news clippings, statements, Senate bills, form letters, broadsides
- Academic Freedom, Philadelphia, 1949-1960 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  Cases, news clippings, correspondence, quarterly publication
- Academic Freedom, Philadelphia, 1954-1956 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  Publication, reprint, brief, news clippings, form letter
- Academic Freedom, Philadelphia, Barrows Dunham, 1955-1956 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  News clippings, correspondence
- Academic Freedom, Poison Pen, 1953-1955 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  Correspondence, post cards
- Academic Freedom, May Quinn Case, 1946-1950 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  News clippings, briefs, cases, photocopies, program, announcements, publication, press releases, memo, conference, form letter, broadsides, correspondence
- Academic Freedom, Radio Broadcasts, ABC Television "Should Political Affiliations of Teachers Be Investigated?", 1949 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  Correspondence, publication, statements
- Academic Freedom, Radio Broadcast CBS Television, "Should Communists Be Barred from Teaching in our Schools?", 1949 (Box 15, Folder 8)
- Academic Freedom, Radio Broadcast (General), 1948 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  Script, form letter, correspondence, envelope
- Academic Freedom, Dorothy Rand, 1949-1952 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  Correspondence, telegram, statement, activity observations, teaching record, brief, interview, bulletins, broadsides
- Academic Freedom, Louis Samet, 1950 (Box 16, Folder 1)
- Academic Freedom, Sylvia Schneiderman, 1950 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  News clippings, correspondence, telegram, press releases, resolutions, announcements
- Academic Freedom, Science and math teachers, 1953-1955 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  Press release, correspondence, form letter
- Academic Freedom, Paul Seligman, 1954 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  Correspondence, statements, briefs, news clippings, interview, press release
- Academic Freedom, Mary Siskind, 1949-1950 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  Correspondence, certificate of termination
- Academic Freedom, Morris Skovran, 1952-1953 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  Interview, summary of record, statement, case, resolution, correspondence, form letters
- Academic Freedom, Joyce Sparer, 1952-1953 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  Interviews
- Academic Freedom, Abraham Squire, 1952-1955 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  Case, exceptions to the report, interview, news clippings, memo, correspondence, form letters
- Academic Freedom, Appeals to Commissioner, Abraham Squire, 1954 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  Appeal, cases, exceptions to report, correspondence
- Academic Freedom, Statements by prominent people, 1953 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  Magazine, correspondence, pamphlet, news clippings, address, release
- Academic Freedom, Janet Marshall Stevenson, (University of Southern California), 1952-1953 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  Correspondence, public interest paper
- Academic Freedom, Students, 1947-1954 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  News clippings, resolution, form letter, publication, articles
- Academic Freedom, Students, 1955-1957 (Box 16, Folder 13)
  Pamphlet, news clippings, correspondence, publication, form letter
- Academic Freedom, Summer Pay, 1953-1954 (Box 16, Folder 14)
  Press releases, collection sheet, appeals, correspondence
- Academic Freedom, Supreme Court Justices, 1961-1962 (Box 17, Folder 1)
- Academic Freedom, Morris Swadesh, 1949-1950 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  Case, statements, press releases, memo, bulletins, briefs, correspondence, form letters, recommendation for appointment
- Academic Freedom, Suspension of 8, Action of miscellaneous organizations, etc., 1951-1953 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  Statement, reports resolution, news clipping, correspondence, form letters
- Academic Freedom, Suspension of 8, American Civil Liberties Union Brief (Box 17, Folder 4)
  Brief; no date.
- Academic Freedom, Suspension of 8, Appeals to State Supreme Court and Appellate Division, 1950-1952 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  Correspondence, transcripts of interviews, notices of application
- Academic Freedom, Suspension of 8, Back Pay, 1950-1952 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  Telegrams, brief, report, correspondence, news clippings, appeal
- Academic Freedom, Suspension of 8, Board of Education (re Kiendl's recommendation), 1950-1951 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  Form letters, news clipping, telegrams, press releases, exhibit
- Academic Freedom, Suspension of 8, Board of Education Trials, 1952-1953 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  Journal, correspondence, opening statement, news clipping, form letter, minutes, press release, remarks, summons
- Academic Freedom, Suspension of 8, Theodore Brameld, 1924-1933 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  Form letter, pamphlet, Journal
- Academic Freedom, Suspension of 8, Clippings, 1952-1953 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  News clippings, publication, program
- Academic Freedom, Suspension of 8, Correspondence, 1950-1955 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  Form letters, correspondence, press release, news clipping, minutes, report, telegrams
- Academic Freedom, Suspension of 8, Correspondence, 1952-1953 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  Press release, form letter, correspondence
- Academic Freedom, Suspension of 8, Abraham Feingold, 1950-1951 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  Reports of the Trial Examiner
- Academic Freedom, Suspension of 8, David Friedman, 1949-1959 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  Opening statement, circular, bulletins, analysis of brief, cases, investigation, correspondence, (Folder #230-1-16-53; correspondence, memo, photocopy, special investigation, cases)
- Academic Freedom, Suspension of 8, Mark Freidlanda, 1951-1952 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  Correspondence, telegram, findings of fact, speeches, news clippings, bulletin
- Academic Freedom, Suspension of 8, Individual Records, 1949-1950 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  Receipt, correspondence, form letters, statements, memo, pamphlet, leaflets, interviews, press releases, record of 8 suspended, teachers, news clippings
- Academic Freedom, Suspension of 8, International Support, 1950-1951 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  Telegram, correspondence, minutes, international bulletins, excerpts and remarks, reprints
- Academic Freedom, Suspension of 8, Theodore Kiendl, Trial Examiner, 1950 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  Form letter, correspondence, memo, news clipping, press releases
- Academic Freedom, Suspension of 8, Legal Action -Bill of Particulars, 1952 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  Correspondence, press release, case
- Academic Freedom, Suspension of 8, Legal Action -Witt and Cramer, 1950 (Box 19, Folder 5)
- Academic Freedom, Suspension of 8, Legal papers filed, 1951 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  Press releases, briefs, correspondence
- Academic Freedom, Suspension of 8, Hearings, Arthur Levitt, 1952 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  Cases
- Academic Freedom, Suspension of 8, Levitt Report and Exceptions to report, 1952-1953 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  Press release, correspondence, minutes, report
- Academic Freedom, Suspension of 8, Levitt's summation, 1952 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  summation and argument
- Academic Freedom, Suspension of 8, Mimeographed and Printed, 1952 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  Form letters, releases, statements, bulletin, court documents
- Academic Freedom, Suspension of 8, Teachers, 1949-1952 (Box 20, Folder 1a)
  Pamphlets, newspaper clippings, form letters
- Academic Freedom, Suspension of 8, Current Letters of Protest to Moss, 1950-1951 (Box 20, Folder 2)
- Academic Freedom, Suspension of 8, Newspaper Clippings, 1950-1951 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  Clippings, articles
- Academic Freedom, Suspension of 8, Order of Trials, 1950 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  Clippings, correspondence
- Academic Freedom, Suspension of 8, Organizations and Individual Support, 1950 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  Correspondence, releases, articles
- Academic Freedom, Suspension of 8, Outside Trial Examiner, 1950 (Box 21, Folder 1-2)
  Correspondence, release, court documents, clippings, statement
- Academic Freedom, Suspension Of 8, Pamphlets, 1950 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  Pamphlets, articles, clippings
- Academic Freedom, Suspension of 8, Support from Parents Association, 1950-1951 (Box 21, Folder 4)
- Academic Freedom, Suspension of 8, Poison Pen Letters, 1950-1951 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  Photocopy, correspondence, post cards, news clippings
- Academic Freedom, Suspension of 8, Poison Pen Letters, 1952 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  Post cards
- Academic Freedom, Suspension of 8, Resolutions by faculty groups, 1950 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  resolutions, correspondence
- Academic Freedom, Suspension of 8, Isadore Rubin, 1947-1950 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  Leaflet, post cards, note, statements, memo, reports, press release, brief, broadside, post card cross reference sheets
- Academic Freedom, Suspension of 8, Isadore Rubin, 1950 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  Correspondence, brief, reports, notice of pleading
- Academic Freedom, Suspension of 8, schools, parents, 1950 (Box 21, Folder 10)
  Statements, resolutions, correspondence, memos, notes
- Academic Freedom, Suspension of 8, Statements, releases, etc, 1952-1953 (Box 21, Folder 11)
  Press releases, news clipping, resolutions
- Academic Freedom, Suspension of 8, T.U. Briefs, statements, press releases, 1950 (Box 21, Folder 12)
  Correspondence, bulletins, post cards, articles, form letters, news clipping, pamphlets, broadside, resolutions, statements, petitions, invitations
- Academic Freedom, Suspension of 8, trials -Exceptions filed by counsel, 1951 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  Correspondence, exceptions filed by counsel
- Academic Freedom, Suspension of 8, Trials -David L. Friedman, 1950-1958 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  Press release, opening statement, briefs, correspondence, pamphlet, index
- Academic Freedom, Suspension of 8, Trials (Memos, procedures, etc.), 1950 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  Legal documents, correspondence, memo, press information sheet
- Academic Freedom, Suspension of 8, Trials -Trial Examiner's Recommendation, 1951 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  Reports of the Trial Examiner, press release
- Academic Freedom, Suspension of 8, further witch-hunts, 1951 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  Correspondence, telegram, memo, press releases
- Academic Freedom, Suspension of 8, Celia Lewis Zitron, 1932-1950 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  Press releases, correspondence, form letters, interviews, post card, photocopy, supervision reports, individual rating reports, news clippings
- Academic Freedom, W. Lou Tandy, 1953 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  News clippings, correspondence, resume (including photo), statement, list of signers, qualifications and experience
- Academic Freedom, Thompson Case, 1940-1948 (Box 22, Folder 8)
  Memo, statements, an analysis of a brief, press releases, resolutions, correspondence, form letters, briefs, news clippings, telegrams, appeal
- Academic Freedom, Thompson (Francis J.) Case, 1947-1948 (Box 22, Folder 9)
  Press releases, statement, correspondence, an analysis of a brief
- Academic Freedom, Thompson Case, Bucci Brief, 1948 (Box 22, Folder 10)
  Memo in opposition to Brief, an analysis of brief, correspondence, news clippings
- Academic Freedom, Town Hall Concert and Rally, 1951 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  Correspondence, script, excerpts from address, telegram, news clippings
- Academic Freedom, Trials, 1953-1954 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  News clippings, press information, press release, report, exceptions to report, correspondence, form letters, subpoena
- Academic Freedom, Lionel Trilling, 1953-1954 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  Correspondence, news clippings, release
- Academic Freedom, Samuel Wallach, 1948-1952 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  Correspondence, form letters, news clippings, telegrams, leaflets, memo, interview, statement, press releases, photocopy
- Academic Freedom, University of Washington, 1948-1951 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  Summary, report, memo, list of signers, correspondence, publication, brief, news clippings, leaflet
- Academic Freedom, "What's Happening in the N.Y.C. Schools?" Meeting - City Center, 1955-1956 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  Press release, bulletin speech, correspondence, invitation, news clipping
- Academic Freedom, Witch-hunt, 1947-1955 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  Memo, editorial, press releases, resolution, inquiry, minutes, brief, correspondence, form letters, statements, bulletins ,news clippings
- Academic Freedom, Local Witch-hunt, 1949 (Box 23, Folder 8)
  Correspondence, resolution, pamphlet, leaflet
- Academic Freedom, Protests to Board of Education against witch-hunts, 1950 (Box 23, Folder 9)
  Correspondence, form letters, press release
- Academic Freedom, Witch-hunt, 1948-1952 (Box 23, Folder 10)
  Bulletins, press releases, statements, resolution, outlines, correspondence, form letters
- Academic Freedom, Renewed Witch-hunts, 1951 (Box 23, Folder 11)
  Press release, correspondence, statement, news clipping
- Academic Freedom, Board of Education, Renewed Witch-Hunts, 1951-1954 (Box 23, Folder 12)
  News clipping, press releases, bulletin, correspondence, form letters, broadside, sermon
- Academic Freedom, Witch-hunt, 1952-1953 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  Correspondence, form letters, bulletins, editorial, press releases, telegram, news clipping, publications
- Academic Freedom, Renewed Witch-hunt, "Lying, Jailing Teachers", 1954 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  Press release
- Academic Freedom, Witch-hunt, 1955-1960 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  Bulletin, news clippings, correspondence, publication
- In re file of Irving Adler, report of Arthur Levitt Committee of the Board of Education, 1952 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  Case, report
- In re Irving Adler Appeal Case, Supreme Court, 1952 (Box 25, Folder 1a)
  Papers on Appeal
- Affiliation Question, AFL-CIO?, 1937 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  Correspondence; Agreement (1951) See: Teachers Union Agreement
- American Association of University Professors, 1953 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  Comments, statement, correspondence, form letter; American Association of University Professors See: Academic Freedom
- American Civil Liberties Union, 1948-1955 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  Correspondence, telegram, news clippings, bulletins reprints, list of publications, post cards, pamphlets
- American Civil Liberties Union, 1952-1959 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  Program, list of publications, correspondence, form letters, news releases
- AFL '35 and '36 charter revocation, 1935-1936 (Box 25, Folder 6)
  Reports, correspondence, form letters, substitute resolution, statement, telegrams, report of proceedings
- AFT and charter revocation, 1935 and 30 attempts, 1935-1936 (Box 25, Folder 7a)
  Reports, speech, program, leaflets, bulletins, telegram, memo, resolution, cases, form letters, correspondence, hearing
- AFT, Local 5, 1923-1941 (Box 25, Folder 8)
  Reports, leaflet, program, resolution, amendments to constitution, correspondence, publications, ticket, handbook
- AFT, Local 5, 1931-1935 (Box 25, Folder 9)
  Form letters, correspondence, resolutions, notes, publications
- American Federation of Teachers, W.P. A., miscellaneous material, 1934-1938 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  Correspondence, report
- Americans For Democratic Action, 1953-1958 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  Correspondence, form letters, statement, receipt, telegram
- American Jewish Congress, Supreme Court of the State of N.Y., County of Albany, brief, 1949 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  Brief
- American Peace Crusade, 1951 (Box 26, Folder 4)
  Telegrams, leaflets, correspondence, memo, bulletin report
- Application forms - new teachers, 1963 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  Application forms, news clippings, correspondence, salary schedule, list of requirements
- Arts and Social Committee, 1949-1951 (Box 26, Folder 6)
  Correspondence, songs
- Association of Retired Teachers, 1957-1962 (Box 26, Folder 7)
  Bulletins, correspondence, form letters, post card; Barnes Bill See: Academic Freedom, PTA Loyalty Oath Blease Bill See: Legislation
- Board of Education, re: Case of John K. Ackley, 1941 (Box 26, Folder 8)
  Transcript
- Board of Education, statement of Lewis Balamuth, 1941 (Box 26, Folder 9)
  Statement
- Bazaar (206. 15th St. Club), 1952-1960 (Box 26, Folder 10)
  Correspondence, form letters, report, raffle tickets post card, posters
- In re: Case of Dorothy Block, 1952 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  Case
- Board of Education, 1949-1954 (Box 27, Folder 2)
  Form letter, correspondence, publications
- Board of Education, Bureau of Child Guidance Matters, 1947-1962 (Box 27, Folder 3)
  Broadsides, newsletter, multi form letter, correspondence, release, clipping, survey, salary schedule
- Board of Education, Church and State, 1955-1956 (Box 27, Folder 4)
  Form letters, press release, news clippings, pamphlet, moral and spiritual guide
- Board of Education, Curriculum, 1955-1959 (Box 27, Folder 5)
  Release, correspondence
- Board of Education, re: Education policies from 1963 (Box 27, Folder 6)
  Clippings, correspondence, form letter
- Board of Education, Fact Finding Committee, 1951 (Box 27, Folder 7)
  Report
- Board of Education cases, re: case of Philip Foner and Arthur R. Branhet, 1941 (Box 27, Folder 8)
  Transcripts
- Board of Education (General), 1948-1956 (Box 27, Folder 9)
  Statement, press release, correspondence, form letters
- Board of Education, Charles Gilman, 1947-1955 (Box 27, Folder 10)
  Correspondence, news clipping
- Board of Education, Superintendent of Schools, Clavin E. Gross, 1962-1963 (Box 27, Folder 11)
  Correspondence, clippings, release, issue of Staff Bulletin
- Board of Education, Guidelines to decentralization, 1961-1962 (Box 27, Folder 12)
  Report, releases
- Board of Education, Informer policy, action again faculties and teacher organizations, 1955-1960 (Box 27, Folder 13)
  Minutes, correspondence, form letters, statement, resolutions, news clippings
- Board of Education, Informer policy, action again newspapers and periodicals, 1955-1960 (Box 27, Folder 14)
  Editorial, correspondence, form letters, news clippings, publication, bulletin
- Board of Education, Informer policy, action again Unions, 1954-1955 (Box 27, Folder 15)
  Correspondence, form letter, telegram, resolution poster
- Board of Education, Informer policy, appeals for reinstated, 1958-1963 (Box 28, Folder 1-1a)
  Press releases, statement, telegram, correspondence form letters, memo, hearing, brief, list of signers of teachers petition
- Board of Education, Informer policy, board meeting, resolution, 1955 (Box 28, Folder 2)
  Form letter, statement, news clippings
- Board of Education, Informer policy, correspondence from Teachers Union, 1954-1959 (Box 28, Folder 3)
  Correspondence, telegram, press release, case, news clipping, information sheet
- Board of Education, Informer policy (General and miscellaneous), 1955 (Box 28, Folder 4)
  Press releases, memo, note, correspondence, accounts of news stories
- Board of Education, Informer policy, legal charges, 1955 (Box 28, Folder 5)
  Cases, news clippings, announcement, correspondence
- Board of Education, Informer policy, legal Commissioner Wilson's Decision, 1955 (Box 28, Folder 6)
  Appeal
- Board of Education, Informer policy, Harvey Matusow, 1952-1955 (Box 28, Folder 7)
  Press release, correspondence, resume, resolutions, photocopies of correspondence, poster
- Board of Education, Informer Policy, memo material, Teachers Union, 1954-1958 (Box 28, Folder 8)
  Correspondence, form letters, information sheet, press release, statement, resolution
- Board of Education, Informer policy, pro, 1954-1955 (Box 28, Folder 9)
  Statement, publication, news clippings
- Board of Education, Informer policy, suit for back pay (Douglas and Levine), 1962-1963 (Box 28, Folder 10)
  Correspondence, appeal
- Board of Education, Informer policy, State Supreme Court Hearing, 1956 (Box 28, Folder 11)
  Hearings, briefs
- Board of Education, Timone Resolution, 1945-1950 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  List of ministers, books reviewed, analysis of brief statement, brief, press release, news clippings, bulletins, photocopy, bibliography
- Board of Education, Timone Resolution to ban T.U., 1950 (Box 29, Folder 2)
  Post card, correspondence, open form letter, broadside, resolution, telegrams, related material
- Board of Education Cases, against Zitron, Friedman et al, 1950 Teachers Hearings (Box 30, Folder 1)
  cases (7), 1 bd. vol.
- Board of Education of the City of New York Case against Alice B. Citron, 1950-1951 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  Cases, reports of trial examiner, memos
- Board of Education Cases, file of Daniman et al, exhibit files, 1952-1955 (Box 31, Folder 2)